<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<GameData>
	<LocalizedText>
		<!--Search Terms-->
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_INDUSTRY">
			<Text>Ngành công nghiệp</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_INDUSTRIES">
			<Text>Các ngành nghề</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_CORPORATION">
			<Text>Tập đoàn</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_CORPORATIONS">
			<Text>Tập đoàn</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_MONOPOLY">
			<Text>Sự độc quyền</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_MONOPOLIES">
			<Text>Độc quyền</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_PRODUCT">
			<Text>Sản phẩm</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_TERM_PRODUCTS">
			<Text>Các sản phẩm</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!-- Game Mode Concept -->
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_CONTENT_TITLE">
			<Text>Các ngành nghề, Độc quyền &amp; Tập đoàn</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_WELCOME_TITLE">
			<Text>Chào mừng</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_WELCOME_PARA_1">
			<Text>Bạn tận hưởng những thứ xa xỉ của mình, nhưng có lẽ đã đến lúc huy động chúng để kiếm lời. Chế độ Độc quyền và Tập đoàn cho phép bạn xây dựng các Ngành xung quanh các tài nguyên Xa xỉ, mang lại các phần thưởng cụ thể tùy thuộc vào tài nguyên, thành lập Tập đoàn để cải thiện các sản lượng đó, sản xuất các Sản phẩm độc đáo – các thương hiệu đóng vai trò là Công trình vĩ đại về kinh tế và cuối cùng là bảo mật a Sự độc quyền. Chế độ này là một chế độ quan trọng trong mọi khoảng thời gian, nhưng thực sự sẽ diễn ra trong trò chơi sau này.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_INDUSTRIES_TITLE">
			<Text>Establishing Industries</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_INDUSTRIES_PARA_1">
			<Text>Once a civilization has improved two of the same type of Luxury resource and has completed the Currency technology they have the opportunity to establish an Industry around that resource. Resources owned by city-states also count toward this requirement if the player is suzerain of the city-state. This is done by using a Builder’s charge on top of an existing Improvement on any one of the Luxury resources. Only one Industry is allowed in a city at a time.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_INDUSTRIES_PARA_2">
			<Text>In addition to providing Great Merchant points, Industries grant particular bonuses to their city based on the type of resource they improve:[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Amber: +25% [ICON_Faith] Faith yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Citrus: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward military units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Cocoa: +20% Growth and +3 [ICON_Housing] Housing.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Coffee: +20% [ICON_Culture] Culture yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Cotton: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward military units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Diamonds: +25% [ICON_Gold] Gold yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Dyes: +25% [ICON_Faith] Faith yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Furs: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward civilian units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Gypsum: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward buildings.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Honey: +20% Growth and +3 [ICON_Housing] Housing.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Incense: +25% [ICON_Faith] Faith yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Ivory: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward military units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Jade: +25% [ICON_Gold] Gold yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Marble: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward buildings.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Mercury: +15% [ICON_Science] Science yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Olives: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward civilian units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Pearls: +25% [ICON_Faith] Faith yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Salt: +20% Growth and +3 [ICON_Housing] Housing.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Silk: +20% [ICON_Culture] Culture yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Silver: +25% [ICON_Gold] Gold yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Spices: +20% [ICON_Culture] Culture yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Sugar: +20% Growth and +3 [ICON_Housing] Housing.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Tea: +15% [ICON_Science] Science yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Tobacco: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward military units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Truffles: +25% [ICON_Gold] Gold yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Turtles: +15% [ICON_Science] Science yield.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Whales: +30% [ICON_Production] Production toward military units.[NEWLINE][ICON_BULLET] Wine: +20% [ICON_Culture] Culture yield.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_CORPORATIONS_TITLE">
			<Text>Công ty sáng lập</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_CORPORATIONS_PARA_1">
			<Text>After researching Economics, and after securing at least three instances of the same Luxury resource and establishing an Industry, it’s time to found a Corporation. These require a Great Merchant instead of a Builder to create, and the Great Merchant is retired once the Corporation is created. Tập đoàn can only be built on top of Industry improvements. Tập đoàn grant double the Industry bonus for the appropriate resource to their home city. You can name your Corporation whatever you like, or use the automated name generator!</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_CORPORATIONS_PARA_2">
			<Text>There can only be one Corporation for each Luxury resource in the world, but Tập đoàn can be put 'out of business' if an opposing player manages to control more instances of the resource than the owning player. Once an opponent secures a controlling interest in another Corporation's resource, they can form their own Corporation around it, and the original owner's Corporation is removed.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_PRODUCTS_TITLE">
			<Text>Tạo sản phẩm</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_PRODUCTS_PARA_1">
			<Text>Once you’ve established a Corporation around a specific luxury resource, you can make a unique Product – a brand. These are similar to Great Works, but instead of being housed in museums, they are stored in new Great Work slots in Stock Exchange or Seaport buildings. Once placed, Products provide the benefits of an Industry, giving whatever bonus their original Luxury resource provided to their new city. You can move your Product to any city you like with the appropriate Great Work slot.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_MONOPOLIES_TITLE">
			<Text>Đảm bảo độc quyền</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_CONCEPTS_PAGE_MONOPOLIES_CHAPTER_MONOPOLIES_PARA_1">
			<Text>Chủ nghĩa tư bản có thể phát triển mạnh nhờ thương mại tự do, nhưng những thương nhân hiểu biết biết cách loại bỏ đối thủ cạnh tranh của họ. Kiểm soát 60% hoặc nhiều hơn các trường hợp trên thế giới của một tài nguyên Xa xỉ sẽ cấp cho bạn Quyền độc lập đối với Xa xỉ đó. Mỗi độc quyền cung cấp [ICON_Tourism] Du lịch cho người chơi sở hữu, dựa trên số lượng tài nguyên được kiểm soát, nhân với số lượng nền văn minh nước ngoài không kiểm soát một phiên bản của tài nguyên độc quyền. Độc quyền cũng cung cấp [ICON_Gold] Sản lượng vàng mỗi lượt, bắt đầu từ +5 để kiểm soát mức tối thiểu nhưng tăng lên +10 ở mức 75% và +25 để kiểm soát tất cả các trường hợp. Bổ sung +5 [ICON_GOld] Vàng mỗi lượt được trao cho mỗi nền văn minh lớn mà người nắm giữ Sự độc quyền hiện đang giao dịch. Sau khi nghiên cứu Chủ nghĩa trọng thương, bạn sẽ có thể xem tổng số tài nguyên Xa xỉ trên thế giới, cũng như tỷ lệ phần trăm mà mỗi người chơi hiện đang kiểm soát. Bạn có thể điều khiển nhiều Độc quyền, nhưng điều đó có vẻ hơi tàn nhẫn phải không?</Text>
		</Replace>
		<!--Improvements-->
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_INDUSTRY_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>The term “industry” often calls to mind the Industrial Revolution, with factories filled with steam, and dangerous, whirring machines. But long before the growth of what William Blake called “dark satanic mills”, rulers saw the advantage in bringing people together to intensify their labor. In Classical antiquity as well as beyond, those working in such industries were often those without their own property – most significantly serfs or enslaved peoples (though the workshops surrounding the Egyptian pyramids, contrary to the popular narrative, were worked by wage laborers). As feudalism gave way to the guild system, and then to early modern capitalism, private individuals gained enough money and status to open their own industries, and the stage was set for the history of economics to begin.</Text>
		</Replace>
		<Replace Language='en_US' Tag="LOC_PEDIA_IMPROVEMENTS_PAGE_IMPROVEMENT_CORPORATION_CHAPTER_HISTORY_PARA_1">
			<Text>Edward, Lord Thurlow, is popularly quoted as saying, “Corporations have neither bodies to be punished, nor souls to be condemned, they therefore do as they like.” The modern-day corporation traces its lineage back to the great trading companies of the 16th-19th century. Facing the uncertainty of transcontinental oceanic trade, something greater needed to be made to outlast the possible death of both ship and owner. The trading companies reshaped the world – goods flowed around the world, but in the end, these companies were also victims of their own riches; global instability rose (in part owing to the action of the trading companies) making trade routes riskier, costs rose along with corruption and mismanagement, and eventually their home empires took over and colonialism moved to a more direct and invasive form. But the model of the corporation, and its utility in creating an artificial, imaginary, legal body that separates individuals from potential risk - and liability - remains with us.</Text>
		</Replace>
	</LocalizedText>
</GameData>
